<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/oscal.css"?>
<catalog xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0"
         uuid="fabc0cb6-70d4-4500-894b-f0e082561713">
   <metadata>
      <title>ID.AM-3 with OT Guidance from SP 800-82r3.ipd</title>
      <last-modified>2023-05-01T09:20:27.2164595-04:00</last-modified>
      <version>1.1</version>
      <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
      <link rel="resolution-source" href="csf-oscal-profile-additive-id.am-3.xml"/>
      <link rel="reference" href="#de298731-62fe-409a-b3dd-e7e8bfe688e8"/>
   </metadata>
   <group class="function" id="id">
      <title>IDENTIFY</title>
      <prop name="label" value="ID"/>
      <part name="statement">
         <p>Develop an organizational understanding to manage cybersecurity risk to systems, people, assets, 
                data, and capabilities.</p>
      </part>
      <control class="category" id="id.am">
         <title>Asset Management</title>
         <prop name="label" value="ID.AM"/>
         <part name="statement" class="outcome">
            <p>The data, personnel, devices, systems, and facilities that enable the organization to achieve 
                    business purposes are identified and managed consistent with their relative importance to 
                    organizational objectives and the organization’s risk strategy.</p>
         </part>
         <control class="subcategory" id="id.am-3">
            <title>ID.AM-3</title>
            <prop name="label" value="ID.AM-3"/>
            <part name="statement" class="outcome">
               <p>Organizational communication and data flows are mapped</p>
            </part>
            <part name="guidance"
                  class="supplemental-guidance"
                  ns="https://gitlab.nist.gov/gitlab/rmf-tools">
               <p>Data flow diagrams enable a manufacturer to understand the flow of data
                        between networked components. Documenting data flows enables organizations
                        to understand expected behavior of their networks. This understanding of how
                        devices communicate assists with troubleshooting as well as response and
                        recovery activities. This information can be leveraged during forensic
                        activities or used for analysis to identify anomalies.</p>
            </part>
            <part name="am-specific"
                  class="Additive-specific-guidance"
                  ns="https://gitlab.nist.gov/gitlab/rmf-tools">
               <p>Data flow diagrams for AM processes represent not only the flow of data between
                        networked components, but also relationships between data elements and their
                        impacts on printed parts. AM provides more freedom in design complexity than other
                        manufacturing technologies. Therefore, AM processes are heavily data-driven.  Examples
                        of AM data elements that can be manipulated to adversely affect the manufacturing
                        process include CAD geometry data, material specifications, AM machine function
                        specifications, and process parameters such as layer thickness and infill pattern.
                        Examples of adverse impacts include porosity, tensile strength, anisotropy, surface
                        roughness, and geometric and dimensional inaccuracy.</p>
            </part>
         </control>
      </control>
   </group>
   <back-matter>
      <resource uuid="de298731-62fe-409a-b3dd-e7e8bfe688e8">
         <title>NIST Special Publication 800-53, Revision 5:  <em> Security and Privacy
                Controls for Information Systems and Organizations</em>  (DOI link)</title>
         <rlink media-type="application/pdf"
                href="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.800-53r5"/>
      </resource>
   </back-matter>
</catalog>
