<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/oscal.css"?>
<catalog xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0"
         uuid="a1a1fa5d-a53a-414d-8aed-906b7bb82176">
   <metadata>
      <title>ID.AM-3 with OT Guidance from SP 800-82r3.ipd</title>
      <last-modified>2023-05-01T09:13:56.394251-04:00</last-modified>
      <version>1.1</version>
      <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
      <link rel="resolution-source" href="csf-oscal-profile-ot-id.am-3.xml"/>
      <link rel="reference" href="#de298731-62fe-409a-b3dd-e7e8bfe688e8"/>
   </metadata>
   <group class="function" id="id">
      <title>IDENTIFY</title>
      <prop name="label" value="ID"/>
      <part name="statement">
         <p>Develop an organizational understanding to manage cybersecurity risk to systems, people, assets, 
                data, and capabilities.</p>
      </part>
      <control class="category" id="id.am">
         <title>Asset Management</title>
         <prop name="label" value="ID.AM"/>
         <part name="statement" class="outcome">
            <p>The data, personnel, devices, systems, and facilities that enable the organization to achieve 
                    business purposes are identified and managed consistent with their relative importance to 
                    organizational objectives and the organization’s risk strategy.</p>
         </part>
         <control class="subcategory" id="id.am-3">
            <title>ID.AM-3</title>
            <prop name="label" value="ID.AM-3"/>
            <part name="statement" class="outcome">
               <p>Organizational communication and data flows are mapped</p>
            </part>
            <part name="guidance"
                  class="supplemental-guidance"
                  ns="https://gitlab.nist.gov/gitlab/rmf-tools">
               <p>Data flow diagrams enable a manufacturer to understand the flow of data
                        between networked components. Documenting data flows enables organizations
                        to understand expected behavior of their networks. This understanding of how
                        devices communicate assists with troubleshooting as well as response and
                        recovery activities. This information can be leveraged during forensic
                        activities or used for analysis to identify anomalies.</p>
            </part>
            <part name="ot-specific"
                  class="OT-specific-guidance"
                  ns="https://gitlab.nist.gov/gitlab/rmf-tools">
               <p>Organizations should consider the impact on OT systems from the use of
                        automated data flow mapping tools that use active scanning or require
                        network monitoring tools (e.g., in-line network probes). Impacts could be
                        due to the nature of the information, the volume of network traffic, or
                        momentary disconnection of manufacturing system components from the network.
                        Consider using data flow mapping tools that utilize these methods during
                        planned downtime.</p>
            </part>
         </control>
      </control>
   </group>
   <back-matter>
      <resource uuid="de298731-62fe-409a-b3dd-e7e8bfe688e8">
         <title>NIST Special Publication 800-53, Revision 5:  <em> Security and Privacy
                Controls for Information Systems and Organizations</em>  (DOI link)</title>
         <rlink media-type="application/pdf"
                href="https://doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.800-53r5"/>
      </resource>
   </back-matter>
</catalog>
